# **ICARDO ERIKSON**

# Senior Software Engineer

▼ Teresina, Pl. Brazil

+55 92 98226 1492

@ ricardo@ricardoerikson.me

ricardoerikson.me

aithub.com/ricardoerikson

in linkedin.com/in/ricardoerikson

# WHO AM I?

I have 15 years of experience working as a software engineer. I've had the opportunity to collaborate with key players of the software industry by building software for the web, mobile devices, distributed systems, and cloud environments. I'm looking for positions to evolve my career and skills with the following stack: Golang, Python, Javascript, TypeScript, Angular, React, AWS, and Docker.

# TOP TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Golang, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript

Cloud (AWS) Cognito, EC2, ECR, CodeArtifact, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline, RDS

Databases MSSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, Postgres

Frontend ReactJS, Angular CSS Bootstrap, Tailwind Other Docker, Git

# **EXPERIENCE**

2/2021 - present Remote Part-time

### Front-end Engineer | DevOps Engineer

Furukawa Electric LatAm

Working as a front-end engineer using Angular and building CI/CD pipelines. Key achievements:

· Built the authentication workflow using AWS Cognito.

· Built the deployment pipeline using AWS cloud environment.

Angular / AWS / Linux

11/2020 - present Remote

### Tech Lead | Golang Engineer

BairesDev Inc.

Working with the Abbott's US cloud solutions team (BairesDev's client). Key achievements:

- · Reduced the overall system overload by splitting long-running operations into batches of smaller ones.
- Improved the API security by identifying and fixing brute force attack vulnerabilities.

Golang / Docker / EC2 / Python

## 8/2016 - 10/2020 Sabbatical | Ph.D. Research | Trading Career

I took a professional sabbatical to improve my academic qualifications and apply my programing knowledge to other areas. Key achievements:

- · Developed a 4-year Ph.D. research in the area of recommender systems where I had the opportunity to use Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, and scikit-learn) to perform extensive data analysis and data visualization to build recommendation models.
- · Started a career in the financial market as a sole trader exploring algorithmic trading and building data analysis tools with Python.

Python / Flask / Pandas / NumPy / Docker / Angular

6/2015 - 7/2016 Manaus, AM, Brazil

### **Senior Software Engineer**

IATECAM

Worked as a senior software engineer, full-stack web developer in web projects using Java, and PHP. Key achievements:

- · Participated in key projects that helped the company to achieve the Level G of the MPS.BR, a QA certification program created by SOFTEX.
- · Helped to define source code comment styling and a branching model to track project features from requirements to source code using Git.

Java / PHP / JavaScript / Angular

3/2008 - 5/2015 Manaus, AM, Brazil Part-time

### **Research Assistant**

**Digital Television Laboratory - UFAM** 

Worked as a research assistant of the Special Interest Group on Software Engineering, Embedded Systems and Automation (SEESA) at the Digital Television Laboratory.

11/2013-3/2015 Manaus, AM, Brazil

### **Lead Software Engineer**

**CETELI - Samsung R&D Center** 

Worked as a technical lead in software projects for mobile and web platforms. Responsible for technical decisions with Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and PHP. Key achievements:

· Built the configuration management process, and the infrastructure for the CI/CD pipelines in development and testing environments.

Java / PHP / JavaScript / Android

4/2010 - 8/2012 Manaus, AM, Brazil

**Tech Lead** 

**CETELI - Nokia Institute of Technology** 

Worked as a tech lead in software projects for mobile devices. Key achievements:

· Coordinated and developed 30 mobile apps for Nokia devices that were published in the Nokia

Qt / QML / JavaScript / HTML / CSS

8/2007 - 2/2008 Teresina, PI, Brazil

Freelance Web Developer

Mundi Tecnologia

Worked as a web developer using technologies such as PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

PHP / JavaScript / HTML / CSS

**EDUCATION** 

02/2021 Belo Horizonte, MG, Brazil

Ph.D Degree in Electrical Engineering Research Area: Recommender Systems Federal University of Minas Gerais

08/2010 Manaus, AM, Brazil Master's Degree in Electrical Engineering

Federal University of Amazonas

Research Area: Software Components and Design Patterns

12/2006 Teresina, PI, Brazil Technologist Degree in Systems Analysis and Development

Federal Institute of Technology of Piauí

Research Area: Digital Television

# LANGUAGES

Portuguese native English fluent German elementary